bluebeam.com 2019-12-12

# Privacy Policy | Bluebeam, Inc.

* * *

Bluebeam’s Privacy Policy was updated on June 1, 2018.

Protecting your privacy is important to us at Bluebeam, Inc. (" _Bluebeam_ "). When you use Bluebeam’s websites, products and services (our “ _Services_ ”), you share information with us. This Privacy Policy covers how we collect, store, disclose, transfer, and use information. 

* * *

### CONSENT

By using our Services, you consent to the collection and use of personal and non-personal information as described in this Privacy Policy so please read it carefully and let us know if you have any questions.

* * *

### PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES

We may modify or update this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we change this Privacy Policy in a material way, a notice will be posted on our website (www.bluebeam.com) along with the updated Privacy Policy. If you use our Services after an update has been made to this Privacy Policy, you consent to the changed policy.

* * *

### INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND USE

We collect and use personal information (e.g. names, addresses, telephone numbers, e-mail addresses, company names, titles, and credit card data) in connection with the operation of our Services when you have voluntarily provided such information to us (e.g., through trial downloads of our software, contact inquiries, purchases and/or use of our products and services, etc.), when adequate consent is granted by you, or on the basis of a statutory provision. As a general rule, we will use such information only for the purpose for which you provided the information to us, e.g. to answer your inquiries or grant you access to certain information or offerings. You are not required to provide Bluebeam with your information; however, if you chose not to in some cases we will not be able to provide you with our Services or respond to your inquiries.

We collect and use your information in three basic ways:

  1.  ** _Information You Give Us._** We collect, store and use: 
    * Your email address if you communicate with us by email, as well as other information that you might supply voluntarily in your communications;
    * Your email address if you elect to receive our newsletter and other electronic communications from us. You can opt-out of receiving such communications at any time by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of each email we send;
    * Your name, email address, telephone number and company name when you elect to download a trial version of our software products;
    * Some or all of the following information when you (i) purchase products or services from us, (ii) when you create a user account with us, or (iii) elect to attend online or in-person training or events with us: your name, email address, mailing address, telephone number, company name, company address, job title and credit card information. We do not give out your credit card or other account information to third parties unless you authorize us to do so or if it is necessary to fulfill our responsibilities, including, but not limited to, delivering a product or service that you order.
  2.  ** _Information We Collect From Your Use of Our Services._**
    * When you use our Services, we gather some information automatically and store it in log files. We collect, store and use your Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, location, referring websites and/or applications, the number of times you visit an individual website page, date/time stamps, Internet service provider (ISP), information about your device (such as device name, what devices you use, your operating system, memory available, etc.) and your browser type, and clickstream data.
    * When you access password-protected areas for account holders, we collect, store and use your username, computer name, IP address, transaction information, pages and content accessed by you, and preferences.
    * We also collect, store and use data and information in a manner and form that on its own does not permit the direct association with any specific individual. We may collect, use, transfer and disclose non-personal information for any purpose.

 **Information Collected Through Cookies and Similar Technologies.**  
Bluebeam may also use cookies and other technologies to receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with our Services. A cookie is a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your device when you use our Services. Cookies may store unique identifiers, user preferences and other information.

We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as non-personal information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Similarly, to the extent that non-personal information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some website features or services may not function properly without cookies. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service, including for storing user preferences, tracking user trends, and providing relevant information to you.

 **Information Collected Through Google Analytics.**  
We use a tool called “Google Analytics” and may use other third party analytic tools to collect information about the use of our Services. Google Analytics collects anonymized information, such as how often users visit a Bluebeam website and what pages they visit when they do so. We only use the information we get from Google Analytics to improve our Services. Google Analytics does not collect your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your device to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit or use our Services, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your usage of our Services is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/analytics/terms/us/) and the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

  3.  ** _Information We Receive From Third Parties._**
    * You may be asked to provide personal information to one of our authorized third party partners (e.g. authorized resellers, event collaborators, and educational service providers) (each a “ _Service Partner_ ”). Bluebeam and our Service Partners may share your personal information but only to the extent necessary to carry out the purpose for which you provided the information to us or our Service Partner, e.g. to provide you with access to our Services that are supported by Bluebeam’s partner.
    * A person or company may procure our Services for you, as their employee, to use at work. Your employer may give us your personal information in order for you to make use of the Services or you may be required to establish a user account with us to access the Services. User accounts require that you provide us with an email address. Other Services may require that we receive your name, title, email address, computer name, and IP address.

* * *

### HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

We use your information to:

  * communicate with you – to respond to your email and other inquiries and requests, to send you newsletters and other information you sign up to receive from us, to send you information concerning any purchases you have made with us (e.g. receipts, license information, etc.), and to send you updates or notices that we think may be of interest to you.
  * provide and improve our Services – to diagnose technical problems and to customize your experience with our Services.
  * protect our Services – to ensure only you and those you authorize have access to your account.

We use your information in combination with other user information to understand and analyze trends, administer the Services, learn about user behavior, improve our Services and gather demographic information. We may also use this information in our marketing and promotional activities. We may also combine your information with other generally or publicly available information to help us identify visitors' preferences or interests. We may provide your information to companies that assist us in these activities, such as helping us fulfill your request for a product, service or information or to tailor advertising that we think may be of interest to you (e.g. to allow third parties to tailor our ads to you on third party services). We do not sell your information to anyone.

* * *

### INTERACTIONS WITH THIRD PARTIES

#### Service Partners - Generally.

We use Service Partners to perform supporting functions for the various Services we offer, such as payment processing, cloud storage providers, analytics providers, product training and online learning opportunities, job postings and applicant tracking, and customer research and surveys. Our Service Partners are NOT permitted to use the information collected from you for any purpose other than performing support functions for Bluebeam. In addition, we require that all Service Providers use reasonable safeguards to protect the limited set of your information that they may have access to.

#### Service Partners - Authorized Resellers and Distributors.

At times we may make certain portions of your information available to our authorized resellers and distributors to help Bluebeam provide our Services to you. For example, if you initiate a license of a Bluebeam software product through an authorized reseller, you authorize Bluebeam and that reseller to exchange information you provide during the license and registration process. We allow authorized resellers and distributors to access information regarding the licenses that they sold, which may include some or all of your information if you are a contact under an applicable license.

#### Protection of rights.

We will release your information if we believe that such action is necessary to: (1) comply with the law, legal process, litigation or requests from governmental authorities (worldwide), (2) enforce our terms and conditions, including any applicable terms of use, user agreements or license agreements, (3) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Bluebeam, its employees, other Service users, or (4) the relevant third party in the event of a reorganization, merger or sale of Bluebeam or any of its subsidiaries or affiliates to a third party.

#### Links to Third Party Websites, Products and Services

Our Services may include links to third party websites, product or services or use or offer products or services from third parties. Information collected by third parties is governed by their privacy policies and practices. We recommend you read and become familiar with the privacy policies of all parties with which you interact.

#### Anonymous Data.

In all other circumstances, if we disclose any information to a third party it will be in the form of aggregated statistical data that does not identify any user individually. This anonymous information may include, for example, the purchasing patterns, trends, preferences and other collective characteristics of our users in general.

* * *

### INTERNATIONAL USERS

Bluebeam’s Services, which allow you to collaborate with other users of our Services around the globe, require by their nature that data flow from the European Union (“EU”) (and other countries) to the United States (“US”) and back. To ensure that EU personal information is adequately protected when transferred outside of the EU, the Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC and, as of May 25, 2018, the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) mandates that such transfers take place using certain legal mechanisms as described here: <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu_en>. Bluebeam is committed to achieving compliance with the GDPR across all of our Services. You may see changes to our policies and procedures that reflect this commitment.

When transferring data from the EU and other countries, Bluebeam relies upon a variety of legal mechanisms, including contracts with our users and the European Commission-approved Standard Contractual Clauses for our EU based users.

#### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield.

Bluebeam also complies with the EU-U.S. and Swiss–U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and/or Switzerland, as applicable, to the United States. Bluebeam has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of notice, choice, accountability for onward transfer, security, data integrity and purpose limitation, access, recourse enforcement and liability. In cases of onward transfers of data, received pursuant to the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks, Bluebeam is potentially liable. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield principles, the Privacy Shield principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

Bluebeam is subject to oversight by the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.  
JAMS is the US-based independent organization responsible for reviewing and resolving complaints about our Privacy Shield compliance — free of charge to you. We ask that you first submit any such complaints directly to us via [privacypolicy@bluebeam.com](mailto:privacypolicy@bluebeam.com). If you aren't satisfied with our response, please contact JAMS at <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield>. In the event your concern still isn't addressed by JAMS, you may be entitled to a binding arbitration under Privacy Shield and its principles.

* * *

### CONTROL OF YOUR INFORMATION

#### Access

 _Studio User Accounts_

By signing into your Studio user account within the Revu® application, navigating to the Studio Preferences section, and editing your information.

 _Bluebeam University Accounts_

By signing into your user account, navigating to the My Profile section, and editing your information; or  
By contacting us at [training@bluebeam.com](mailto:training@bluebeam.com).

 _Licensing and Purchase Information_

You can correct and update licensing information by emailing us at [registration@bluebeam.com](mailto:registration@bluebeam.com).

 _Bluebeam Developer Network_

By signing into your BBDN user account, navigating to the Preferences section, and editing your information.

#### Opt-Out

 _Marketing Emails:_ If you no longer wish to receive marketing emails from Bluebeam, you can opt-out of receiving such communications at any time by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of each email we send. Also in the email footer, you will find an option to Manage Subscriptions if you’d like to adjust your subscription preferences.

 _Product and Service Emails:_ If you no longer wish to receive emails concerning the products and service you have licensed and/or purchased from us, you can opt-out of receiving such information at any time by contacting us at [registration@bluebeam.com](mailto:registration@bluebeam.com). If one of our Service users invites you to collaborate with them as part of their use of the Services, we cannot prevent you from receiving those user initiated emails.

 _Regular Mail/Telephone/In-Person:_ If you no longer wish to be contacted by Bluebeam via regular mail, telephone or in-person sales calls, you can opt-out by emailing us at [registration@bluebeam.com](mailto:registration@bluebeam.com).

 _Service Partners:_ To opt-out of receiving communications from our Service Partners, you must contact the Service Partner directly.

When you opt-out or close your user account, we may retain a copy of your information for archival purposes and to avoid identity theft or fraud.

* * *

### CHAT ROOMS AND FORUMS

We may from time to time provide chat sessions and rooms, forums, beta testing feedback services, message boards and/or bulletin boards (a “forum”) for users to exchange information. Please remember that any information disclosed in these areas may be viewed by other users of the forums or the general public depending on how access to the forums are established. If you post in a forum, please use care not to disclose any confidential or personal information. Bluebeam is not responsible or liable for the uses that others may make of any information you post in a forum.

* * *

### SECURITY

We use industry standard physical, technical and administrative security measures and safeguards to protect the confidentiality and integrity of your information. When your information is stored by Bluebeam, we use computer systems with limited access housed in facilities using physical security measures. Cloud data is stored in encrypted form including when we utilize third-party storage. All of our cloud services leverage Transfer Layer Security (TLS) to encrypt and protect information during transit.

It is your responsibility to protect the security of your login information. Please note that e-mails and other communications you send to us are not encrypted. We strongly advise you not to communicate any confidential information through these means.

* * *

### CALIFORNIA DO NOT TRACK

Bluebeam does not track its customers over time or across third party websites to provide targeted advertising and therefore does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals. However, some third party sites do keep track of your browsing activities when they serve you content, which enables them to tailor what they present to you. If you are visiting such sites, most browsers allow you to set the DNT signal on your browser so that third parties (particularly advertisers) know you do not want to be tracked.

* * *

### SUMMARY

If you have any questions concerning this policy please send an email to us at [privacypolicy@bluebeam.com](mailto:privacypolicy@bluebeam.com).
